## **Sherwood Williamson**

07988 698548

sherwoodwilliamson@outlook.com 1 York Place, York Street, East Markham, Newark, NG22 0QW

## Personal profile

Computer Science, Engineering and Maths student at Tuxford Academy Post 16. I have extensive experience with programming languages such as Python and C#, demonstrated by development of personal projects on my own time and working in a team. I am also experienced in the usage of CAD-CAM softwares such as Autodesk Inventor to develop high-level CAD portfolios at industry standard.

### **Skills**

#### **Technical skills**

I have created several personal programming projects - on my own and in a team - which have honed and developed my skills in specific programming languages.

#### **Problem solving**

During my work at a local charity, focusing on data management and organisation, I have to overcome logical thinking problems on how to use the database to effectively organise the data and fill in any inconsistencies, such as duplicates or gaps in data.

### Working under pressure

During development of coursework for my Engineering BTEC GCSEs and A-Levels, I have had to meet time-sensitive deadlines and hand in dates which required strict time management to ensure the work was finished to an appropriate standard and quality.

### Work experience

July 2023 - June 2024

## Data Management Assistant - Active Fusion

Management of data and maintaining a database appropriately and efficiently for a local charity ensuring young people and children have the opportunity to be physically active. This involves uploading information collected by coaches from holiday activity camps and events appropriately and efficiently to the database. This also involves working as a team with other members of staff to coordinate ongoing jobs and tasks that need performing and what improvements could be made to the database.

July 2023 - June 2024

# Part-Time Casual Coach - Active Fusion

Working part-time when available as a casual coach on activity camps and events ran by a local charity ensuring young people and children have the opportunity to be physically active. This involves taking care of the young children and ensuring their safety if out in public spaces such as the park. This also has involved helping the lead coach in running activities or games for the children during the day, demonstrating communication skills and leadership skills.

### **Education**

September 2021 - June 2023

### **GCSE Qualifications** - Tuxford Academy

8 in Computer Science, Distinction 2 in Engineering and Digital Media, 6 in Maths, 6-6 in Combined Science, 6 in English Language and Literature respectively, and a 6 in Geography.

### Other interests

July 2024 - Present

### **Work Experience @ The Curve Consulting**

Worked with a small developer team to design a software solution for a client brief provided by The Curve Consulting to demonstrate their line of work. The project we created was a solution for tracking expense reports for the company, designing a website interface using HTML and a backend system with PHP and MySQL to manage and safely store user accounts, as well as allow users to manage their forms of reports to their "Line Manager" chosen within their profile, as well as an email notification system to directly inform a manager to approve a form, instead of replying on them to manually check on a spreadsheet, improving efficiency and approval times. Skills such as leadership, project management, teamwork and problem solving were all used.

### References

Mrs Rebecca Davis

**Tuxford Academy** - Head of Computing and ICT 01777 870001 rdavis@tuxford-ac.org.uk

Mr Keanu Simpson-Baker

**Tuxford Academy** - Head of Design and Technology 01777 870001 ksimpsonbaker@tuxford-ac.org.uk